Guide to the Robert K. Merton Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Writings, 1931-2002
  - Subseries VII.2: Articles By, 1931-2002
    - Chronological
      - "Practical Problems and the Uses of Social Science" / Edward C. Devereux, Jr., 1964 (Box 307, Folder 9)
      - "Sources of Stress in Society," 1964 (Box 307, Folder 10)
      - "The Environment of the Innovating Organization," 1965 (Box 307, Folder 11)
      - "Dilemmas of Democracy in the Voluntary Association," 1966 (Box 307, Folder 12)
      - "Making it Scientifically: A Review Essay of The Double Helix," 1968 (Box 307, Folder 13)
      - "Making it Scientifically: A Review Essay of The Double Helix" 1968 (Box 308, Folder 1)
      - "Observations on the Sociology of Science," 1968, (2 Folders) (Box 308, Folder 2-3)
      - "The Matthew Effect in Science: the Reward and Communication Systems of Science are Considered" / Harriet A. Zuckerman
        - General, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1967-1979 (Box 308, Folder 5)
        - Requests, 1965-1968 (Box 308, Folder 6)
      - "Seminars Without Constraints," 1968 (Box 308, Folder 7)
      - "Foreword to a Preface for an Introduction to a Prolegomenon to a Discourse on a Certain Subject," 1969 (Box 308, Folder 8)
      - "Sociology, Jargon and Slangish," 1969 (Box 308, Folder 9)
      - "Behavior Patterns of Scientists"
        - General, 1969 (Box 308, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 308, Folder 11)
        - First Draft, undated (Box 308, Folder 12)
      - "The Social Nature of Leadership, Congress Papers of the 14th Quadrennial Congress," 1969 (Box 308, Folder 13)
      - "The Ambivalence of Organizational Leaders," 1970 (Box 308, Folder 14)
      - "Sociology of Refereeing," 1971 (Box 308, Folder 15)
      - "Insiders and Outsiders: An Essay in the Sociology of Knowledge"
        - General, 1969-1971 (Box 308, Folder 16)
        - Correspondence, 1970-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 309, Folder 1-2)
        - R.N. Saxena Festschrift, 1968-1971 (Box 309, Folder 3)
      - "Insiders and Outsiders: A Chapter in the Sociology of Knowledge," 1972, (2 Folders) (Box 309, Folder 4-5)
      - "Patterns of Evaluation in Science: Institutionalization, Structure and Functions of the Referee System" / Harriet A. Zuckerman, 1971, (2 Folders) (Box 309, Folder 6-7)
      - "The Precarious Foundations of Detachment in Sociology," 1967-1971 (Box 309, Folder 8)
      - "The Competitive Pressures (I): The Race for Priority" / Richard Lewis, 1971 (Box 309, Folder 9)
      - "Age, Aging, and Age Structure in Science" / Harriet A. Zuckerman
        - General, 1969-1972 (Box 309, Folder 10)
        - Draft, undated (Box 309, Folder 11)
      - "On Discipline Building: The Paradoxes of George Sarton" / Arnold Thackray, 1972, (2 Folders) (Box 310, Folder 1-2)
      - "A Professional School for Training in Social Research" / Paul Lazarsfeld, 1972 (Box 310, Folder 3)
      - "Structural Analysis in Sociology," 1975 (Box 310, Folder 4)
      - "Thematic Analysis in Science: Notes on Holton's Concept," 1975 (Box 310, Folder 5)
      - "Social Knowledge and Public Policy"
        - General, 1975 (Box 310, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 310, Folder 7)
        - Drafts, 1973 (Box 310, Folder 8)
        - Edits, 1974-1975 (Box 310, Folder 9)
      - "On the Origin of the Term: Pseudo-Gemeinschaft," 1975 (Box 311, Folder 1)
      - "The Ambivalence of Scientists: A Postscript," 1976 (Box 311, Folder 2)
      - "The Uses of Institutionalized Altruism," 1976 (Box 311, Folder 3)
      - "Institutionalized Altruism: The Case of the Professions / Thomas Gieryn," 1976 (Box 311, Folder 4)
      - "The Sociological Study of Scientific Specialties" / Thomas Gieryn, 1978 (Box 311, Folder 5)
      - "Remembering Paul Lazarsfeld," 1979 (Box 311, Folder 6)
      - "On the Oral Transmission of Knowledge," 1980 (Box 311, Folder 7)
      - "Remembering the Young Talcott Parsons," 1980 (Box 311, Folder 8)
      - "The Shoulders of Giants," 1980 (Box 311, Folder 9)
      - "Citation Classic: Social Theory and Social Structure," 1980 (Box 311, Folder 10)
      - "Merton on New York," 1981 (Box 311, Folder 11)
      - "On Sociological Ways of Thinking about Thinking and Thought," 1981 (Box 311, Folder 12)
      - "Remarks on Theoretical Pluralism," 1981 (Box 311, Folder 13)
      - "Our Sociological Vernacular," 1981 (Box 311, Folder 14)
      - "On the Fleckian Sociological Epistemology and Structural Analysis in Sociology," 1981 (Box 311, Folder 15)
      - "Alvin W. Gouldner: Genesis and Growth of a Friendship," 1982 (Box 311, Folder 16)
      - "Florian Znaniecki: A Short Reminiscence," 1983 (Box 311, Folder 17)
      - "Client Ambivalence in Professional Relationships: The Problem of Seeking Help from Strangers" / Vanessa Merton; Elinor Barber--Draft, 1983 (Box 311, Folder 18)
      - "Sociology of Science in Poland," 1983 (Box 311, Folder 19)
      - "Socially Expected Durations: A Case Study of Concept Formation in Sociology," 1971-1982, (2 Folders) (Box 311, Folder 20-21)
      - "The Fallacy of the Latest Word: The Case of Pietism and Science," 1984 (Box 312, Folder 1)
      - "Texts, Contexts and Subtexts: An Epistolary Foreword," 1969-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 312, Folder 2-3)
      - "The Kelvin Dictum and Social Science: An Excursion into the History of an Idea" / David L. Sills; Stephen M. Stigler, 1960-1984, (3 Folders) (Box 312, Folder 4-6)
      - "Science and the Fight to be First," 1984 (Box 312, Folder 7)
      - "George Sarton: Episodic Recollections by an Unruly Apprentice," 1985 (Box 312, Folder 8)
      - "Basic Research and Its Potentials of Relevance," 1985 (Box 312, Folder 9)
      - "The Historicist-Presentist Dilemma," 1985 (Box 313, Folder 1)
      - "The Focused Interview & Focus Groups: Continuities and Discontinuities"
        - General, 1987-1992 (Box 313, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 313, Folder 3)
      - "Three Fragments from a Sociologist's Notebooks: Establishing the Phenomenon, Specified Ignorance and Strategic Research Materials," 1987 (Box 313, Folder 4)
      - "André Cournand, 1895-1988," 1987 (Box 313, Folder 5)
      - "Reference Groups, Invisible Colleges and Deviant Behavior in Science," 1988 (Box 313, Folder 6)
      - "Sociological Resonances: The Early Franco Ferrarotti and a Transatlantic Colleague," 1988 (Box 313, Folder 7)
      - "Some Thoughts on the Concept of Sociological Autobiography," 1988 (Box 313, Folder 8)
      - "The Matthew Effect in Science, II: Cumulative Advantage and the Symbolism of Intellectual Property"
        - General, 1988 (Box 313, Folder 9)
        - Flemish Translation, 1988 (Box 313, Folder 10)
      - "The Sorokin-Merton Correspondence on Puritanism, Pietism and Science," 1988 (Box 313, Folder 11)
      - "Le Molteplici Origini e il Carattere Epiceno del Termine Inglese Scientist," 1988-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 313, Folder 12-13)
      - "Unanticipated Consequences and Kindred Sociological Ideas: A Personal Gloss," 1989 (Box 313, Folder 14)
      - "Unanticipated Consequences and Kindred Sociological Ideas: A Personal Gloss," 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 314, Folder 1-2)
      - "Uber die Vielfatigen Wurzeln und den Geschlechtslosen Charakter des Englischen Wortes 'Scientist': Eine Episode im Wechselspiel von Wissenschaft, Sprache und Gesellschaft," 1990 (Box 314, Folder 3)
      - "Remarks on Becoming an Honorand of Jagiellonian University: Social Time and Socio-Cognitive Networks," 1990 (Box 314, Folder 4)
      - "STS: Foreshadowings of an Evolving Research Program in the Sociology of Science," 1990 (Box 314, Folder 5)
      - "Epistolary Notes on the Making of a Sociological Dissertation Classic: The Dynamics of Bureaucracy," 1990 (Box 314, Folder 6)
      - "Social Science Quotations: Who Said What, When, and Where" / David L. Sills, 1991 (Box 314, Folder 7)
      - "Social Science Quotations" / David L. Sills, 1992 (Box 314, Folder 8)
      - "Patterns in the Scholarly Use of Quotations" / David L. Sills, 1992 (Box 314, Folder 9)
      - "Genesis of the Field of 'Science, Technology and Society'," 1993 (Box 314, Folder 10)
      - "Durkheim's Division of Labor in Society: A Sexagenarian Postscript," 1994 (Box 314, Folder 11)
      - "A Life of Learning: Charles Homer Haskins Lecture," 1994 (Box 314, Folder 12)
      - "Scientists' Competitive Behavior Is Not Peculiar to Our Competitive Age," 1994 (Box 314, Folder 13)
      - "The Cultural and Social Incorporation of Sociological Knowledge" / Alan Wolfe, 1995 (Box 314, Folder 14)
      - "Opportunity Structure: The Emergence, Diffusion, and Differentiation of a Sociological Concept," 1995 (Box 314, Folder 15)
      - "The Thomas Theorem and The Matthew Effect," 1995 (Box 314, Folder 16)
      - "Teaching James Coleman," 1997 (Box 314, Folder 17)
      - "De-Gendering 'Man of Science': The Genesis and Epicene Character of the Word Scientist"
        - General, 1997, (2 Folders) (Box 314, Folder 18-19)
        - Responses, 1997-1998 (Box 314, Folder 20)
      - "Working with Lazarsfeld," 1998 (Box 314, Folder 21)
      - "Working with Lazarsfeld," 1998 (Box 315, Folder 1)
      - "On the Garfield Input to the Sociology of Science: A Retrospective Collage," 2000 (Box 315, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished or Unidentified
      - "Climates of Personal Relations," undated (Box 315, Folder 3)
      - "Crime and the Anthropologist: An Historical Postscript," 1982-1984 (Box 315, Folder 4)
      - "Discussion of Bernard J. Stern 's 'The Family and Cultural Change'," undated (Box 315, Folder 5)
      - "E.A. Hooton: Cassandra or Sibyl?," circa 1940 (Box 315, Folder 6)
      - Facts and Figures for Carnegie Tech Paper, 1960 (Box 315, Folder 7)
      - Festschrift for Rene Konig (cancelled), 1979-1981 (Box 349, Folder 11)
      - "The Functions of Citations in the Reward System of Science," 2002 (Box 315, Folder 8)
      - International Sociological Association Paper--Notes, 1959 (Box 315, Folder 9)
      - "Notes on Learning and Working," 1981 (Box 315, Folder 10)
      - "Oscillations in Scientific Theories," 1933 (Box 315, Folder 11)
      - "A Sampler of Comments on Design for a National Longitudinal Study of School Desegregation," 1974 (Box 315, Folder 12)
      - Self-Emancipation Proclamation, 1982 (Box 315, Folder 13)
      - "Social Structure and Public Opinion"--Notes for Draft, 1947 (Box 315, Folder 14)
      - "Some Patterns in Scientific Development," 1986 (Box 315, Folder 15)
      - "Some Remarks on the Emergence of Functional Analysis in Sociology," 1941 (Box 315, Folder 16)
      - "A Typology of Ethnic Discrimination and Prejudice"--Annotated Draft, undated (Box 315, Folder 17)
      - "The Underwood Study: Perspectives and Comments," undated (Box 315, Folder 18)
    - General
      - Blurbs for Others, 1963-1993, (3 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 6 to 8)
      - Prosaic Essays in Sociology, 1960, undated (Box 412, Folder 9)
    - Chronological
      - "Studies in Radio and Film Propaganda" / Paul Lazarsfeld--Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 412, Folder 10)
      - "Role of the Intellectual in Public Bureaucracy"--Proofs, undated (Box 412, Folder 11)
      - "The American Soldier"--Drafts and Notes, 1950 (Box 413, Folder 1)
      - "Notes on Sociology in the U.S.S.R."--Skinner, Fred, undated (Box 413, Folder 2)
      - "The Matthew Effect in Science: the Reward and Communication Systems of Science are Considered" / Harriet A. Zuckerman
        - General, 1966-1975 (Box 413, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1968-1986 (Box 413, Folder 4)
        - Drafts and Notes, 1965-1986, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 413, Folder 5 to 6)
        - Responses, 1968-1968 (Box 413, Folder 7)
        - Various Editions, 1965, 1985-1987 (Box 413, Folder 8)
      - "Age, Aging, and Age Structure in Science" / Harriet A. Zuckerman--Notes and Research, 1967-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 413, Folder 9 to 10)
      - "Three Fragments from a Sociologist's Notebooks: Establishing the Phenomenon, Specified Ignorance and Strategic Research Materials"
        - Inscriptions, 1987-1988 (Box 413, Folder 11)
        - Responses, 1987-1988 (Box 414, Folder 1)
      - "A Life of Learning: Charles Homer Haskins Lecture"
        - Inscriptions, 1998-1999 (Box 414, Folder 2)
        - Spanish Translation, 1996-1997 (Box 414, Folder 3)
      - "Opportunity Structure: The Emergence, Diffusion, and Differentiation of a Sociological Concept"--Inscriptions, 1998 (Box 414, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished
      - "The Caucasian Problem and How it Grows," 1947 (Box 414, Folder 5)
      - "How to Stop Smoking-With Comparative Ease," 1975 (Box 414, Folder 6)
      - "Jargon, Sociology, and Anglish," undated (Box 414, Folder 7)
      - "Oscillations in Scientific Theories," 1933 (Box 414, Folder 8)
      - "Unanticipated Consequences of the Reward System in Science: A Model of the Sequencing of Problem-Choices" / Robert C. Merton
        - General, 1988-2002, (4 Folders) (Box 414, Folder 9 to 12)
        - Bibliography undated (Box 415, Folder 1)
        - Carayol, Nicolas, 2001-2002 (Box 415, Folder 2)
        - Coleman, James, 1982-1988 (Box 415, Folder 3)
        - Comments from Others, 1983-1988 (Box 415, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 415, Folder 5)
        - Drafts, 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Rationality and Society, 1989, 2002 (Box 415, Folder 8)
        - Research
          - General, 1971-1999 (Box 415, Folder 9)
          - General, 1971-1999, (6 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 1 to 6)
          - General, 1971-1999, (4 Folders) (Box 417, Folder 1 to 4)
          - Hechter, Michael, 1989 (Box 417, Folder 5)
          - Notes, 1975-1989 (Box 417, Folder 6)
          - Yellin, Joel, 1972-1987 (Box 417, Folder 7)
        - Stigler, George J., 1979 (Box 417, Folder 8)
      - "Who's Aware of Virginia Woolf's 'Man Called Richardson'? A Query in the History of Sociology," 1977-1983 (Box 417, Folder 9)
    - Chronological
      - "Socially Expected Durations: A Case Study of Concept Formation in Sociology"--Notes, 1983 (Box 495, Folder 6)
      - "A Life of Learning: Charles Homer Haskins Lecture"
        - Academy of Music Archives, 1990-1994 (Box 495, Folder 7)
        - Americanization--Salient Statuses and Assimilation, 1992-1994 (Box 495, Folder 8)
        - Birth
          - Date, 1989-1990 (Box 495, Folder 9)
          - Obscured by Other Events, 1993 (Box 495, Folder 10)
        - Chance Processes, 1992 (Box 495, Folder 11)
        - Checking Memories by Published Materials, undated (Box 495, Folder 12)
        - Corrected Pages, 1994 (Box 495, Folder 13)
        - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 495, Folder 14)
        - Deleted Passages from Early Drafts, 1994 (Box 495, Folder 15)
        - Drafts, 1994 (Box 495, Folder 16)
        - Harvard Yarns, 1975-1988 (Box 496, Folder 1)
        - Houdini the Young Magician, undated (Box 496, Folder 2)
        - Inscriptions and Mailing Lists, 1994 (Box 496, Folder 3)
        - Institutional Density, 1993 (Box 496, Folder 4)
        - Invitation, 1992-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 496, Folder 5 to 6)
        - A Jewish American, 1990-1993 (Box 496, Folder 7)
        - Letters not Responded to, 1994-1996 (Box 496, Folder 8)
        - Map and Other Slides, 1992-1994 (Box 496, Folder 9)
        - Materials Used, 1993-1994 (Box 496, Folder 10)
        - My Early Years, 1990-1993 (Box 496, Folder 11)
        - My "Public Jewish Identity," 1972-1993 (Box 496, Folder 12)
        - Notes, 1992-1994 (Box 497, Folder 1)
        - Penultimate Version, 1993-1994 (Box 497, Folder 2)
        - Possible Inserts, 1991-1994 (Box 497, Folder 3)
        - Previous Haskins Lectures, 1992-1994 (Box 497, Folder 4)
        - Regrets, 1994 (Box 497, Folder 5)
        - Responses, 1987-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 497, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Samuelson, Paul, 1993-1994 (Box 497, Folder 8)
        - Self-Fulfilling Prophecy--Diffusion into Fiction and Vernacular, 1993 (Box 497, Folder 9)
        - Short Memories, 1992-1993 (Box 497, Folder 10)
        - Short Version of On the Shoulders of Giants Origins, 1993 (Box 497, Folder 11)
        - South Philadelphia, 1992-1994 (Box 497, Folder 12)
        - Temple University--Not Accredited--Bernard, L.L., 1931 (Box 497, Folder 13)
        - Thematics, 1990, undated (Box 498, Folder 1)
        - To Consult for Final Revisions, 1992-1994 (Box 498, Folder 2)
        - Valuable Comments, 1994 (Box 498, Folder 3)
      - "The Cultural and Social Incorporation of Sociological Knowledge" / Alan Wolfe
        - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 498, Folder 4)
        - Drafts and Final, 1993-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 498, Folder 5 to 6)
        - First Abstracts--Wolfe, Alan, 1993-2000 (Box 498, Folder 7)
        - Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 498, Folder 8)
        - Proofs, Edited, 1993-1995 (Box 498, Folder 9)
        - Research, 1980-1996, (4 Folders) (Box 499, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Subseries VII.3: Books By, 1933-2002
    Subseries VII.3 is arranged into three sections: general records; chronologically by publication date; and unidentified or unpublished material. General material pertains to several publications and therefore is not filed with one particular title. These files are typically administrative in nature. Records related to published books include correspondence, contracts with publishers and contributors, reviews, notes, research, and original drafts. Material in this subseries portrays Merton's meticulous research habits and depicts his particular writing methods.
    Of interest is material related to The Travels and Adventures of Serendipity. Merton and Elinor Barber began research on the word serendipity in the 1950s. The project lay dormant for several decades and discussion of publication was revived in the 1990s. The records in this subseries trace the work's progression up through eventual publication plans. As part of their initial research efforts, Merton and Barber asked colleagues to contribute their thoughts and ideas about the term serendipity. These responses, as well as articles written about the term, are located in the alphabetical research section. This section is alphabetized by contributor or author's last name. Also of note is material regarding Merton’s earliest published book, Science, Technology and Society in Seventeenth Century England, which includes correspondence with Pitirim Sorokin. The subseries also contains original drafts and corrections for one of Merton's most well known and well received books, On the Shoulders of Giants.
    All items pertaining to Patterns of Social Life: Explorations in the Sociology of Housing are located in Series VI.
    - General
      - Contracts, 1979 (Box 315, Folder 19)
      - Reviews, 1971-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 315, Folder 20-21)
      - Sales Data, 1999-2000 (Box 316, Folder 1)
      - Translations
        - General, 1989-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 316, Folder 2-3)
        - Chinese, 1989-2000, (2 Folders) (Box 316, Folder 4-5)
        - The Free Press, 1955-1983 (Box 316, Folder 6)
        - Requests, 1953-1974 (Box 316, Folder 7)
        - Spanish, 1992-2000 (Box 316, Folder 8)
    - Chronological
      - Science, Technology and Society in Seventeenth Century England
        - General, 1936-1940, 1967-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 1-2)
        - Comenius, Puritanism and Science Items, 1957-1972 (Box 260, Folder 3)
        - Conferences
          - "Fifty Years after Merton: New Directions in 17th Century Science and Religion," 1988 (Box 260, Folder 4)
          - Van Leer Jerusalem Institute
            - Heilbron, John, 1988 (Box 260, Folder 5)
            - Holton, Gerald, 1984-1988 (Box 260, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence
          - Sorokin, Pitirim, 1933 (Box 260, Folder 7)
          - Turner, Bryan, 1987 (Box 260, Folder 8)
          - Wallner, Mathias, 1988-1989 (Box 260, Folder 9)
        - Externalism and Internalism, 1988, undated (Box 260, Folder 10)
        - I.B. Cohen Volume
          - General, 1988-1989 (Box 260, Folder 11)
          - Afterword, 1988 (Box 260, Folder 12)
          - Correspondence, 1936-1939, 1960-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 13-14)
          - Items Sent, 1934-1942, 1972-1988 (Box 261, Folder 1)
          - Notes, 1984-1989 (Box 261, Folder 2)
        - ISIS Volume, 1988-1990 (Box 261, Folder 3)
        - Original Holograph File, 1935-1950, 1971 (Box 261, Folder 4)
        - Outlines, undated (Box 261, Folder 5)
        - Personal Responses, 1970-1988 (Box 261, Folder 6)
        - Research Notes
          - General, circa 1930s, 1942, 1967, (2 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 7-8)
          - A-F, circa 1930s (Box 261, Folder 9)
          - G-M, circa 1930s (Box 261, Folder 10)
          - N-R, circa 1930s (Box 261, Folder 11)
          - S-Z, circa 1930s (Box 261, Folder 12)
          - Civilizational (Box 262, Folder 1)
          - Darmstaedter Analysis (Box 262, Folder 2)
          - Puritanism, 1951-1961 (Box 262, Folder 3)
        - Reviews, 1937-1940 1971-189, (2 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 4-5)
        - Sorokin Commentary on Puritanism, Pietism and Science, 1935-1939, 1985-1988 (Box 262, Folder 6)
        - Third Edition
          - Bibliography, 1999-2001 (Box 262, Folder 7)
          - Introduction, 1999-2001 (Box 262, Folder 8)
        - Translations
          - Chinese, 1996-1999 (Box 262, Folder 9)
          - Flemish, 1987-1988 (Box 262, Folder 10)
          - Portuguese, 1988 (Box 262, Folder 11)
          - Spanish, 1982 (Box 262, Folder 12)
        - Triplet Material, undated (Box 262, Folder 13)
      - The Family Encounters the Depression: A Re-analysis of Documents /E. W. Burgess et al.
        - General, 1949-1950, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 316, Folder 9-10)
        - Memoranda, 1944 (Box 316, Folder 11)
        - Original Angell Study Interviews, circa 1930s, (3 Folders) (Box 317, Folder 1-3)
        - Typescript, circa 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 317, Folder 4-5)
      - Mass Persuasion--with the Assistance of Marjorie Fiske and Alberta Curtis, 1943-1968 (Box 317, Folder 6)
      - Social Theory and Social Structure
        - Editions
          - Enlarged, 1960-1979 (Box 317, Folder 7)
          - Italian, 1970-1971 (Box 317, Folder 8)
          - Spanish, 2002 (Box 317, Folder 9)
        - Reviews, 1953-1970 (Box 317, Folder 10)
        - Translations
          - Chinese, 1988-2000 (Box 317, Folder 11)
          - Polish, 1981-1983 (Box 317, Folder 12)
      - Reader in Bureaucracy--Edited with Alisa P. Gray; Barbara Hockey; Hanan C. Selvin
        - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 318, Folder 1)
        - Free Press
          - Contracts, 1952 (Box 318, Folder 2)
          - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 318, Folder 3)
        - Moshe Decter Papers, 1950 (Box 318, Folder 4)
        - New Edition, 1962-1963 (Box 318, Folder 5)
        - Permissions, 1950-1951 (Box 318, Folder 6)
      - Focused Interview / Marjorie Fiske; Patricia L. Kendall
        - General, 1982-1992 (Box 318, Folder 7)
        - Administrative, 1958 (Box 318, Folder 8)
        - American Association for Public Opinion Research Conference, 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 318, Folder 9-10)
        - Correspondence, 1944-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 318, Folder 11-12)
        - Drafts and Notes, undated (Box 318, Folder 13)
        - Qualitative Research Consultants Association--50th Anniversary Celebration, 1991-1992 (Box 318, Folder 14)
        - Reviews, 1956-1957 (Box 318, Folder 15)
        - Rough Copy for Revised Draft, undated (Box 318, Folder 16)
        - Rough Copy for Revised Draft, undated (Box 319, Folder 1)
        - Second Edition--Correspondence, 1977-1993 (Box 319, Folder 2)
        - Use of Term by Others, 1980-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 319, Folder 3-4)
      - The Student-Physician: Introductory Studies in the Sociology of Medical Education--Edited with George G. Reader; Patricia L. Kendall